airamerica.com 2009-06-19

# Privacy Policy | Air America Media

Air America Media has created this Privacy Statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy online. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Air America Media web sites. 

We gather certain information that you provide to us, some passively and some actively, and we want to ensure that all users of the Air America Media Site are aware of exactly how and for what purpose that information is being used. 

Air America Media believes that the information you provide to us is essential to your enjoyment and successful use of the Air America Media site. Our collection of information enables us to provide you with a personalized web experience, and assists our sales team and advertisers in efficiently reaching an appropriate audience. The information we request is the minimum we believe necessary to achieve this goal. 

**1\. What data does Air America Media collect?**

a. Certain data is automatically collected from all visitors to the Air America Media site. This data includes your IP address, your computer's operating system, and the type of browser you use to surf the Internet. 

b. Air America Media makes use of cookies on its sites. A cookie is a file transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the website may track your activities on the website. Cookies, by themselves, do not let a website know any personally identifying information about you, such as your real name, address, etc., unless you previously provided that information at the website or have set your preferences in your browser to provide that information. 

Air America Media is not generally interested in any one individual and does not collect personally identifiable information about any one person using cookies. Cookie technology allows Air America Media to keep track of your selections on the Air America Media Site and to try to make sure that you don't see the same ad repeatedly. Cookies are also used to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so that you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit the Air America Media Site. 

c. To access the Air America Media Site, you do not have to provide any personal information. Some features of the Air America Media Site do request personal information of you before granting access. If you wish to participate in the blog features offered on the Air America Media Site, you will be asked to create a username and password to be used when replying to blog entries as well as for your name, e-mail address, and zip code. You will also be asked whether you want to receive future e-communications from Air America Media. 

  1. If you opt for this feature, you must provide a valid e-mail address during the registration process. When replying to these blog posts, you will do so under your chosen username. Please be aware that Air America Media cannot control and assumes no responsibility for the collection, use or misuse of this publicly accessible information by other visitors to the Air America Media Site.  

  2. The Air America Media Site has a newsletter distributed via e-mail. If you choose to subscribe to this feature, you must provide a valid e-mail address. Your e-mail address will be used only by Air America Media for the distribution of the newsletter and any promotions or marketing that we feel may be of interest to you and will not be divulged to any third party, except as required by court order. To no longer receive newsletters from us, please review how in our help section on newsletters. All Air America Media newsletters include an unsubscribe link in at the very bottom. Clicking this link will unsubscribe you immediately.  

  3. Occasionally, Air America Media will request you to fill out a user survey. Such surveys are optional to you, the users, but allow Air America Media to better understand the demographics and interests of our users. Your responses in combination with the responses of our other users help Air America Media to improve the Air America Media Site and attract sponsors and advertisers. Should you choose to participate in such a survey, please note Air America Media's policies regarding the sharing of user information with third parties as stated in paragraph 3. If and when Air America Media does choose to share its user information, it does so only in the aggregate such that the third party will not be able to identify any individual user.   

  4. Air America Media may, occasionally run contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions sponsored by Air America Media or our partners and sponsors. If you are identified as a winner, Air America Media may request your name and mailing address. This information is used to deliver your prize(s). Air America Media may supply third-party sponsors with personal information collected from contests and sweepstakes entrants in connection with certain online contests and sweepstakes. In each such case, Air America Media will disclose to potential entrants that such information will be supplied to a third party, and the identity of such third party, at the time entrant information is collected. Please see Paragraph 3d below for more details.   

  5. If you contact Air America Media through the regular mail or via e-mail, Air America Media may keep a record of that correspondence. Any personally identifiable information on your communication will not be used for a commercial or unlawful purpose.  

  6. Air America Media does not control the acts of its users. All users should be aware that, when they disclose personal information such as their actual name, e-mail address, etc., the information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties outside Air America Media. 

d. The privacy of minors. Air America Media believes that it is particularly important to protect the privacy of minors online. Air America Media defines a "minor" as any person under 13 years of age. Air America Media does not collect personal information about minors. 

e. When you order products from us, we also collect personally identifiable information from you. If you order one of our products or services, we will collect and maintain your name, e-mail address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number, product selections, credit card or other payment information, order number, referring URL, IP address and a password. We collect this, and other information, as disclosed in this policy, in order to fill your order, to communicate with you about your order and to send you promotional materials. Before confirming your order, you will have the opportunity to review the product order form and make changes and additions to the information it contains. These changes will be automatically kept for future use. We use good faith efforts not to provide third parties with access to your individual account information, unless stated otherwise on the Site. We reserves the right to provide non-identifiable consumer data to third parties including, but not limited to, general statistics about pages viewed on our site, sales and other shopping information. 

**2\. How does Air America Media use your information?**

Air America Media puts the non-personally identifiable information passively gathered whenever you visit our sites and the personal information that you voluntarily provide to several uses. 

a. Your IP address is used to assist us in diagnosing problems with our server and network, to administer the Air America Media Site and to provide information to our sponsors and advertisers. 

b. Air America Media may use the information you provide to perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our users and to analyze how and where to invest our resources. 

c. Air America Media may use personal contact information voluntarily provided by you for promotional and/or marketing purposes. 

d. Demographic and profile data is used to tailor our users' experience at the Air America Media Site, directing users to content we think may be of interest to that user, and displaying content for which the user may have shown a preference. 

e. Both our internal sales team and outside advertising firms may utilize the information you provide us to better tailor your experience on the Air America Media Site. Without the data collected, Air America Media would not know what the most popular regions of the Air America Media Site are, Air America Media would not be able to provide an effective forum for our sponsors to advertise in, nor would Air America Media be able to measure which promotions are successful. 

**3\. What information does Air America Media share with third parties?**

a. Unless described herein, Air America Media will not impart to third parties individual users' e-mail addresses or other individual personal information unless required to do so by law. 

b. Companies that place advertising on our sites may have the ability to assign you a separate cookie while you are accessing the Air America Media Site. We do not control these cookies, nor do we have access to this information. The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to you by a third party, our Web advertising partner. Information about your visit to their site, such as number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address, or other personal information), is used to serve ads to you on this site. 

c. From time to time, Air America Media may offer contests and sweepstakes sponsored by third party businesses or in connection with third party content partners. Air America Media may share with such third parties entrant information collected by Air America Media only if the entrant opts in to receive information from such third party. In these types of contests and sweepstakes, Air America Media will disclose to potential entrants that such information will be so supplied and the identity of the third party to whom such information will be supplied at the time entrant information is collected and will provide entrants with the opportunity to opt in to receive such third party information. However, any information supplied to a third party may be retained by such third party and will be out of the control of Air America Media. Air America Media is not responsible for privacy practices or the third parties use of such information. 

d. Air America Media encourages all third parties to adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our users, but Air America Media does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties. 

e. Air America Media responds to subpoenas, warrants or other court orders regarding information that is contained within our access logs concerning any user. Air America Media also reserves the right to release the information concerning a user who we believe is in violation of our content guidelines or United States law, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. Air America Media cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our servers for illegal activities. We also reserve the right to report any illegal activity to law enforcement for prosecution. 

**4\. Financial information.**

Financial information may be requested of you either as part of an online survey the results of which are to be used for demographic analysis purposes or in conjunction with the purchase of goods and services from the Air America Media Site. Financial information will not be shared with anyone outside of Air America Media. 

**5\. How do I opt-out, remove, change, or modify my information?**

You have the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at any time. To change or modify any information you have provided to us from our database please do so through the member profile. To no longer receive newsletters from us, please review how in our help section on newsletters. We will use all reasonable efforts to meet your request within seven (7) days. 

To remove your name from the Air America Media database entirely including, but not limited to, registration for airamericaradio.com: Go to your member profile and simply click on link that says, "Click here to un-register from airamericaradio.com" and confirm. 

**6\. Kids policy.**

The safety of children is very important to Air America Media, and Air America Media recommends that parents review our Privacy Policy before allowing their children to access the Air America Media Sites, especially the blog post areas. Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to anyone online. They should also be instructed not to fill out any forms or register at any domain without a parent's knowledge and consent. Air America Media does not knowingly share personal information about users under the age of 13 with third parties. 

**7\. How does Air America Media protect the user data it collects online?**

Air America Media employs a number of physical, electronic and managerial safeguards to protect collected user data. 

**8\. Disclaimers.**

a. All users should be aware while using any service where you disclose personal information online voluntarily, including in chat areas, on message or bulletin boards, or through e-mail, that such information can be collected and used by others. If you use these services on the Air America Media Site and voluntarily provide any information on our bulletin boards or in chat areas, you do so at your own risk. Air America Media cannot make any representations regarding the security of such transfer of information. 

b. You should be aware that the Air America Media Site contains links to outside sites. Air America Media is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. 

c. Air America Media reserves the right to change or modify this policy at any time by posting such change or modification on this page. The protection of user information is one of the guiding principals behind Air America Media. Because of that stance, you will be notified via e-mail of any changes to the Privacy Policy regarding the way personally identifiable information is used. 

**9\. Contacting Air America Media**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, the practices of the Air America Media Sites, or your dealings with the Air America Media Site, please contact us.  Air America Media reserves the right to change this policy at any time, and users should check this page regularly for such updates. This statement and the policies outlined herein are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal right in or on behalf of any party.
